<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/imagick">imagick</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>3.5.0</v>
 <st>stable</st>
 <l>PHP License</l>
 <m>danack</m>
 <s>Provides a wrapper to the ImageMagick library.</s>
 <d>Imagick is a native php extension to create and modify images using the ImageMagick API.
This extension requires ImageMagick version 6.5.3-10+ and PHP 5.4.0+.</d>
 <da>2021-06-17 16:51:29</da>
 <n>- Fixed multiple parameter information issues found in 3.5.0RC1.
- ImageMagick 7 is still not widely available on systems. So contrary to previous plans, ImageMagick 6 support will continue for now. But users are recommeded to use ImageMagick 7 if possible.
- Method names have been changed to not be all lower case. Both method names and parameter information is built from the Imagick*.stub.php files.
- Prevent accidental creation of zero dimension images. ImageMagick doesn't prevent creation of zero dimension images, but will give an error when that image is used. I don't think this will affect any correctly program, but if it does, and you need to re-enable zero dimension images, please open an issue at https://phpimagick.com/issues
- Various pieces of work have been done to make GOMP not segfault including:
* Call omp_pause_resource_all when available during shutdown.
* Added the 'imagick.shutdown_sleep_count' (default 10) and 'imagick.set_single_thread' (default On). Both of these exist to mitigate the segaults on shutdown.
- Fixes:
* Correct version check to make RemoveAlphaChannel and FlattenAlphaChannel be available when using Imagick with ImageMagick version 6.7.8-x
* Imagick::morphology now no longer ignores channel parameter
* ImagickPixel::setIndex() takes a Quantum value (aka float in HDRI mode, int in non-HDRI mode).
* ImagickPixel::getColorValue() always returns an int value.
- Added:
* PHP 8.0 support.
* Location check for ImageMagick 7 for NixOS and Brew.
* Imagick::houghLineImage(int $width, int $height, float $threshold): bool {}
* Imagick::setImagePixelColor(int $x, int $y, ImagickPixel|string $color)
* Imagick::setImageMask(Imagick $clip_mask, int $pixelmask_type)
* Imagick::getImageMask(int $pixelmask_type)
* Imagick::VIRTUALPIXELMETHOD_DITHER
* Imagick::VIRTUALPIXELMETHOD_RANDOM
* Imagick::COMPOSITE_FREEZE
* Imagick::COMPOSITE_INTERPOLATE
* Imagick::COMPOSITE_NEGATE
* Imagick::COMPOSITE_REFLECT
* Imagick::COMPOSITE_SOFTBURN
* Imagick::COMPOSITE_SOFTDODGE
* Imagick::COMPOSITE_STAMP
* Imagick::COMPOSITE_RMSE
* Imagick::COMPRESSION_DWAA
* Imagick::COMPRESSION_DWAB
* Imagick::EVALUATE_INVERSE_LOG
* Imagick::COLORSPACE_DISPLAYP3
* Imagick::COLORSPACE_ADOBE98
* Imagick::COLORSPACE_PROPHOTO
* Imagick::COLORSPACE_JZAZBZ
* Imagick::DISTORTION_RIGID_AFFINE
* Imagick::DISTORTION_BARRELINVERSE
* Imagick::STATISTIC_ROOT_MEAN_SQUARE</n>
 <f>300657</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/imagick-3.5.0</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.3.5.0.xml"/>
</r>