<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/mysql_xdevapi">mysql_xdevapi</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>8.0.14</v>
 <st>stable</st>
 <l>PHP</l>
 <m>mysqlre</m>
 <s>MySQL X DevAPI for PHP</s>
 <d>The X DevAPI is the new common API for MySQL Connectors built on the X Protocol introduced in MySQL 5.7.12.

The X DevAPI wraps powerful concepts in a simple API.
* A new high-level session concept enables you to write code that can transparently scale from single MySQL Server to a multiple server environment.
* Read operations are simple and easy to understand.

The X DevAPI introduces a new, modern and easy-to-learn way to work with your data.
* Documents are stored in Collections and have their dedicated CRUD operation set.
* Work with your existing domain objects or generate code based on structure definitions for strictly typed languages.
* Focus is put on working with data via CRUD operations. See Section 3.1, “CRUD Operations Overview”.
* Modern practices and syntax styles are used to get away from traditional SQL-String-Building. See Chapter 10, Building Expressions.</d>
 <da>2019-01-23 03:17:59</da>
 <n>WL#12593: DevAPI: Handling of Default Schema
WL#12457: Be prepared for initial notice on connection
WL#12291: automagically resolve path to preferred version of boost on pb2
orabug #28803092 the offset() method requires limit()
orabug #28802524 always use sql()-&gt;execute() instead of executeSql()
orabug #27441854 fetchAll should return an empty array when the result is empty, not (bool)false
orabug #28804413 containers methods
orabug #28802453 TableDelete: offset does not seem useful
orabug #29011588 execute more than once for crud ops with bind causes crash at releasing
orabug #28605347 CollectionFind::offset() without limit() error is unclear
orabug #28803201 FieldMetadata and ColumnResult are returning different information about columns
orabug #28804447 remove client functions
orabug #28802551 Collection::createIndex() create an index on multiple fields
orabug #28804461 ensure groupBy() functionality
orabug #28838435 PHPT tests - make checking results more precise</n>
 <f>443712</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/mysql_xdevapi-8.0.14</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.8.0.14.xml"/>
</r>