<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/winbinder">WinBinder</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>0.46.0</v>
 <st>alpha</st>
 <l>BSD License</l>
 <m>sfrausch</m>
 <s>A Native Windows Binding for PHP</s>
 <d>WinBinder is a new extension that allows PHP programmers to build native Window applications. It wraps the Windows API in a lightweight, easy-to-use library, so that program creation is quick and straightforward.</d>
 <da>2006-06-08 19:49:48</da>
 <n>This is the last maintenance release of the alpha branch. WinBinder now does fully support the following PHP versions: 4.3.10 up to 4.4.2 and 5.0.3 up to 5.1.4.

HIGHLIGHTS:

- added the new Form Editor (FE) developed by Rubem and removed the old Layout Editor (LE)

ENHANCEMENTS:

- improved PHP version checking in winbinder.php

- In PHP.INI for version 5.0 and 5.1: added E_STRICT flag to entry error_reporting

- created PHP 5.1.1 path and project files for lcc-win32

- added and optional extra parameter (usually called $lparam3) to window callback functions. This was done via wbCallUserFunction()

- on windows that have the WBC_RESIZE style, $lparam3 (in the callback function) now receives the size of the client area as a LONG. Usually a call to wb_get_size($window, true) would produce the same effect, but it's there anyway to take advantage of the new $lparam3

- Changes in make_release.phpw:

. even less &quot;USER PARAMETERS&quot; to set up (7 strings only)
. force DEBUG = False in wb_setup.pas
. slight adjustments in screen layout
. more adjustments to include PHP 5.1.1 files
. checks if zip file was actually generated
. other changes

- small changes in welcome.phpw

- examples/hyperlink.phpw: changed to show &quot;finger&quot; cursor and underlined text

- examples/printer.phpw: added example how to print directly from a WinBinder enabled application

- resources/wb.ico: added new WinBinder icon

BUG FIXES:

- wb_generic.inc.php: functions generate_ini and parse_ini do now handle double quotes correctly; fixed missing escaping of the '$' character

- wb_windows.inc.php: function wb_set_selected now processes check boxes in menu items as it should; wb_get_text() now returns an array with the whole contents of a ListView control, as stated in the manual - did return null instead

- solved memory leak that occurred on every function call: added some extra calls to efree() in function wbCallUserFunction() in module phpwb_wb_lib.c

- wb_control.c: Rectified wb_set_range() slider TBM_SETRANGEMAX action and other aspects of this function

- WBC_MOUSEMOVE messages were not being sent in certain situations

- InvisibleArea was subclassed to process and send WM_MOUSEMOVE messages to the callback

- wb_refresh() (and wbRefreshControl()):

. completely rewrote the whole function
. default value of parameter 'now' was changed to TRUE
. now it invalidates and redraws only a part of the screen or control when (still undocumented) xpos/ypos/width/height parameters are passed to it. Was buggy prior to this release.
. probably a bit faster for most operations
. if the wb_refresh() command is issued and the xpos/ypos/width/height are set, the window callback function (in PHP) receives a pointer to rectangle (About to change! Should be the area instead, and an array would be great.) as $lparam3. If wb_refresh() acts on the whole window, $lparam3 is zero.

  Dimensions should be obtained from $lparam3
  as follows:

  $address = wb_peek($lparam3, 16);
  $num = unpack('L4n', $address);
  $xpos = $num['n1'];
  $ypos = $num['n2'];
  $width = $num['n3'] - $xpos;
  $height = $num['n4'] - $ypos;

- Added handling of the official PHP 4.4.2 bug reported at http://bugs.php.net/bug.php?id=36671 and regarding the function file_get_contents in examples/welcome.phpw

- Changes in make_release.phpw:

. now correctly handles/saves the new version no. structure

- Changes in setup:

. many changes and corrections to wb_setup.iss (PHP 5.0 and 5.1, freeimage.dll, etc.)
. separated the script section from wb.iss into wb_setup.pas. A separate file allows correct syntax highlighting in a code editor and allows testing script changes without leaving ISTool (Inno Setup UI)
. other changes

OTHER ACTIVITIES

- updated the PHP 4 engine and the respective extensions to 4.4.2

- removed the redundant PHP binaries and accompanying files (not the extensions) for 5.0.5 and 5.1.2

- uploaded new &quot;minimal&quot; PHP 4.4.2, 5.0.5 and 5.1.2 versions as well as the respective extensions to SF

For further enhancements and bug fixes since the last official release 0.43.164 see the change log.</n>
 <f>1079790</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/WinBinder-0.46.0</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.0.46.0.xml"/>
</r>