<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/apcu">apcu</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>5.1.25</v>
 <st>stable</st>
 <l>PHP License</l>
 <m>nikic</m>
 <s>APCu - APC User Cache</s>
 <d>APC User Caching</d>
 <da>2025-07-28 18:51:09</da>
 <n>- If the cache is full, try to clean up expired entries based on their per-entry hard TTL even
  if the soft apc.ttl is 0. Previously the entire cache was discarded.
- If a new entry cannot be inserted due to fragmentation, the cache will be defragmented,
  combining many small free blocks into one big free block by moving around cache entries.
  This avoids the need to discard the entire cache in more cases.
- The access time (which is used by the soft apc.ttl) is now also updated when using
  apcu_exists().
- apc.entries_hint now defaults to 512 entries per 1MB of shared memory. Previously the
  default was 4096, independent of shm_size. This could lead to a large number of hash
  collisions if shm_size was increased without also increasing entries_hint.
- Added apc.mmap_hugepage_size to use huge pages of a certain size for the apcu shared memory
  segment. This requires support for huge pages to be enabled in the kernel. Note that even if
  this option is not set, shared memory is still configured to use transparent huge pages.
- The apc.shm_segments ini option has been removed. Multiple SHM segments are no longer
  supported. (They were already not supported when using mmap, which is the default mode of
  operation)
- The apc.smart configuration setting should now work more reliably. Values &gt; 1 can be used
  to increase the chance of discarding the entire cache when the amount of memory freed by
  removing expired entries was too small. This could be useful if performance degrades due to
  executing the logic to remove expired entries (+ defragmentation) too frequently during
  periods of high memory usage.
- The number of cache cleanups performed (removal of expired entries) is now available
  in the array returned by apcu_cache_info() (via array key &quot;cleanups&quot;).
- The number of defragmentations performed is now available in the array returned by
  apcu_cache_info() (via array key &quot;defragmentations&quot;).
- Fixed several issues that caused inserting new entries to fail unexpectedly.

Internal changes:
- Fixed -Wclobbered compiler warnings.
- All cache data structures are now relocatable, i.e. independent of the base address of the
  cache. This enables defragmentation support.
- Hash slots now use doubly linked lists. This is necessary for defragmentation.</n>
 <f>94319</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/apcu-5.1.25</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.5.1.25.xml"/>
</r>