<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/wxwidgets">wxwidgets</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>3.0.0.1</v>
 <st>stable</st>
 <l>PHP</l>
 <m>jgmdev</m>
 <s>Cross-platform widget toolkit.</s>
 <d>Wraps the wxWidgets library, which allows to write 
 multi-platform desktop applications that make use of the native 
 graphical components available to the different platforms.</d>
 <da>2014-03-09 17:46:40</da>
 <n>* Added missing wxScrolledWindow methods by enabling wxScrolled, 
  this fixes issue #30 and #32.
* Enabled wxClipBoard::Get() and disabled gargbage collection of 
  native_object on wxDataObject and its childs as wxClipBoard itself, 
  which partially fixes issue #34.
* Added verification of object parameter child types to allow method 
  calls which where failing as described on issue #36. This also 
  completely fixes issue #34, testing may be needed.
* Updated README_MSW adding changes needed to prevent windows xp 
  crashes as described on issue #37.
* Enabled wxNonOwnedWindow::SetShape and fixed wxPrintDialog, 
  wxPageSetupDialog inheritage.
* Removed error messages that appeared when failing to call 
  wxApp::OnInit and wxApp:OnExit.
* Added proper type casting to wxMouseState.
* Should fix and close #44 by doing proper type casting when calling 
  wxKeyboarState methods from child classes.
* Binded the missing wxAuiNotebookEvent event constants which closes #45.
* Enabled more wxStyledTextCtrl methods. 
* Enabled inheritance of wxStyledTextCtrl from wxTextEntry as 
  enabled some more methods.
* Some fixes to the reference and interface generator as 
  simplification of chdir() calls.
* Initial work to support wxInputStream::OnSysRead in order to be 
  able to load images with the wxImage(wxInputStream) constructor.
* Fixed 2 memory leaks, one related to wxEvtHandler::OnEvent and the 
  other related to the creation of new objects.
* Fixed memory leak caused by not uninitializing the properties 
  member of classes like wxPoint when they were destroyed which 
  closes #48, also modified code generator to only add the properties 
  code when needed which made the source and library more clean.</n>
 <f>1785518</f>
 <g>http://pecl.php.net/get/wxwidgets-3.0.0.1</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.3.0.0.1.xml"/>
</r>