<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/wxwidgets">wxwidgets</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>3.0.2.0</v>
 <st>stable</st>
 <l>PHP</l>
 <m>jgmdev</m>
 <s>Cross-platform widget toolkit.</s>
 <d>Wraps the wxWidgets library, which allows to write 
 multi-platform desktop applications that make use of the native 
 graphical components available to the different platforms.</d>
 <da>2015-06-09 08:08:19</da>
 <n>* Updated the thread.php example to work properly.
* Remove delete on the wxThread garbage collector function, which 
  should fix most issues on #84.
* Modified wxWindow::GetHandle to return the XWindowID on Gtk which 
  should really fix #86.
* Enabled wxWindow::GetHandle by casting WXWidget to size_t.
* Enabled wxOutputStream::Write and wxInputStream::Read variations 
  that take a 'void* buf' as argument which should fix issue #87
* Updated version numbers and added userland version constants: 
  WXWIDGETS_LIBRARY_VERSION and WXWIDGETS_EXTENSION_VERSION.
* Added --with-wxwidgets-version to package.xml so 'pecl install 
  wxwidgets' can ask for a different version of wxWidgets library to 
  download and compile.
* Set the default wxWidgets version to download and compile on linux 
  and mac to 3.0.2. Also added a new configure option 
  --with-wxwidgets-version to explicitly change the version of 
  wxWidgets to download, eg: --with-wxwidgets-version=3.0.1
* Forgot to conditionally fetch tsrm on wxAppWrapper.
* Fetch TSRM on wxAppWrapper which probably fixes issue #70
* Unmodified copy of wxImage::GetData to zval which fixes #75.
* Own the data parameter on wxImage SetData to really fix issue #75.
* Custom templates for wxImage GetData and SetData which fix 
  and close #75.
* Updating location of Mac OS X SDK in docs (chrisnharvey).
* Updating docs for building on Mac OS X (chrisnharvey)
* Updating link to heading
* Updating macosx-version-min to 10.9
* Added sdl, sdl_sound as dependencies on archlinux PKGBUILD.
* Updated config.m4 to require sdl and sdl_sound on linux which 
  fixes #2.
* Removed some testing printf code.
* Added some wxApp methods.
* Fix to correctly brake search for wx-config when first found in 
  config.m4 file.
* Added wxPHP shell script in /usr/bin/wxphp.
* Added some wxApp methods.
* Automated Mac OSX detection which should fix #94.
* Simplified README.md and added building steps into INSTALL.md.
* Removed trace of debugging code.
* Merge child class method overrides that differ into parent methods 
  which should fix #97.
* Added drag and drop example.
* Disabled pointer deletion for wxDropTarget and child classes
  to fix segmentation fault which fixes #98.</n>
 <f>1846913</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/wxwidgets-3.0.2.0</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.3.0.2.0.xml"/>
</r>