<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/cubrid">CUBRID</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>8.3.1.0001</v>
 <st>stable</st>
 <l>PHP</l>
 <m>cubrid</m>
 <s>This is the official PHP Extension to connect to CUBRID Database.</s>
 <d>CUBRID is an open source database management system highly optimized for Web applications (http://www.cubrid.org). The current PHP extension is fully compatibly with the latest stable version of CUBRID Database. To post issues and report bugs, please use CUBRID Official Forum at http://forum.cubrid.org.</d>
 <da>2011-01-05 04:12:23</da>
 <n>2008 R3.1 Release

This release is a major release. CUBRID 3.1 Stable has been released. Several new 
features have been added to this version including new BLOB and CLOB data types and 
new APIs in JDBC/CCI which can get foreign key information. Accordingly new functions 
and features are added in this CUBRID PHP version, and some bugs have been fixed.

Functionality added:

- Add more CUBRID-MySQL Compatibility functions:

  cubrid_query
  cubrid_close
  cubrid_error
  cubrid_errno
  cubrid_client_encoding
  cubrid_fetch_array
  cubrid_db_name
  cubrid_ping

- Add Lob related functions:

  cubrid_lob_get
  cubrid_lob_close
  cubrid_lob_size
  cubrid_lob_export
  cubrid_lob_send

Functionality removed:

Glo data type has been removed from CUBRID 3.1, BLOB/CLOB can be used to replace it. So 
removed Glo related functions:

  cubrid_new_glo
  cubrid_save_to_glo
  cubrid_load_from_glo
  cubrid_send_glo

Changed and Enhanced Features:

- Add three new schema type integer constants for cubrid_schema: 

  CUBRID_SCH_IMPORTED_KEYS
  CUBRID_SCH_EXPORTED_KEYS
  CUBRID_SCH_CROSS_REFERENCE

  They can be used to get foreign key information. 

- cubrid_bind support BLOB and CLOB data types.

- cubrid_unbuffered_query now is worthy of its name. It won't need to wait 
  for that all query results have been complete. It will return when the 
  results are being generated, so you can't use cubrid_num_rows and 
  cubrid_data_seek on a result set returned from cubrid_unbuffered_query.

- cubrid_fetch_object: Add new parameters class_name and params, which can 
  pass the name of class to instantiate and the constructor for class_name objects.

- When cubrid_schema and cubrid_col_size fails, return false instead of -1.

Fixed bugs:

- last db connetion/request resource management: If there is no variable to refer these resources, they will be removed by garbage collector.
- cubrid_execute: If cubrid fails to get result info after executing sql statement, there may be memory leak.
- cubrid_disconnect: When disconnecting any db connection, it will always reset the last request and connection info.
- cubrid_unbuffered_query: When query execution fails, it don't free the allocated request resource.</n>
 <f>34942</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/CUBRID-8.3.1.0001</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.8.3.1.0001.xml"/>
</r>