<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/cubrid">CUBRID</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>8.4.1.0001</v>
 <st>stable</st>
 <l>PHP</l>
 <m>cubrid</m>
 <s>This is the official PHP Extension to connect to CUBRID Database.</s>
 <d>CUBRID is an open source database management system highly optimized for Web applications (http://www.cubrid.org). The current PHP extension is fully compatibly with the latest stable version of CUBRID Database. To post issues and report bugs, please use CUBRID Official Forum at http://forum.cubrid.org.</d>
 <da>2012-02-01 00:54:31</da>
 <n>2008 R4.1 Release

This release is a major release. Several new features have been added to this version 
including persistent connecting, query timeout and so on. Accordingly new functions
are added, and several bugs have been fixed.

The following functions have been added:

- cubrid_pconnect
- cubrid_pconnect_with_url
- cubrid_set_query_timeout
- cubrid_get_query_timeout

Changed and Enhanced Features:

1) Reuse the connection established:

For mysql, if a second call is made to mysql_connect() with the same arguments, no new
link will be established, but instead, the connect identifier of the already opened
connection will be returned. The new_link parameter modifies this behavior and makes
mysql_connect() always open a new connection, even if mysql_connect() was called before
with the same parameters. 

To make compatibility with mysql, we add the new_link parameter in cubrid_connect and
cubrid_connect_with_url.

2) Add persistent connection:

We add two functions, cubrid_pconnect and cubrid_pconnect_with_url, to provide persistent
database connections. The parameters of cubrid_pconnect are same with cubrid_connect, and
so do cubrid_pconnect_with_url and cubrid_connect_with_url.

3) Add functions about getting and setting the query timeout time:

If database queries are taking too long to perform, and your application is becoming
unresponsive, you can configure a timeout for database queries. We add two functions
(cubrid_get_query_timeout and cubrid_set_query_timeout) to get and set the query timeout
of database queries.

4) Add a form of the url parameter for cubrid_connect_with_url function:

Support the way without &quot;cci:&quot; in url parameter, that is the url become 
&quot;CUBRID:host:db_name:db_user:.......&quot;

Fixed bugs:

- Fix a bug in cubrid_fetch, cubrid_fetch_row, cubrid_fetch_array, cubrid_fetch_assoc
and cubrid_fetch_object: Modified the return value when there are no more data;</n>
 <f>42446</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/CUBRID-8.4.1.0001</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.8.4.1.0001.xml"/>
</r>