<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/cubrid">CUBRID</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>9.1.0.0004</v>
 <st>stable</st>
 <l>PHP</l>
 <m>cubrid</m>
 <s>This is the official PHP Extension to connect to CUBRID Database.</s>
 <d>CUBRID is an open source database management system highly optimized for Web applications (http://www.cubrid.org). The current PHP extension is fully compatibly with the latest stable version of CUBRID Database. To post issues and report bugs, please use CUBRID Official Forum at http://forum.cubrid.org.</d>
 <da>2013-07-23 02:23:35</da>
 <n>Fixed bugs:
1)[APIS-120] - [PHP]Return value is not correct when passing a date parameter to cubrid_bind method
2)[APIS-121] - [PHP]Return value is not false when passing a invalid time to cubrid_bind method
3)[APIS-358] - [PHP] Create table failed when using default timestamp '2038-01-19 12:14:07'
4)[APIS-364] - [PHP][Windows] the export lob file from db is not correct after import the lob fie into db successfully
5)[APIS-513] - [PHP Static] Cas error code is not expected in Windows
6)[APIS-553] - Manual page for cubrid_close_request() should be edited
7)[APIS-554] - cubrid_connect_with_url example does not have updated connection url
8)[APIS-556] - cubrid_fetch CUBRID_LOB tries to allocate 4 billion bytes
9)[APIS-557] - cubrid_lob2_seek64 example does not work properly
10)[APIS-558] - [PHP]some bug about document
11)[APIS-560] - Cannot load PHP API 9.1.0.0003 in CentOS 5.6: undefined symbol: pthread_create in Unknown on line 0
12)[APIS-562] - Cannot execute DELETE query in CUBRID SHARD via PHP API
13)[APIS-583] - [PHP] The cubrid_get_class_name() function throws a warning if select data from a system table
14)[APIS-586] - [PHP] cubrid_bind() doesn't work properly when insert bit data
15)[APIS-587] - [PHP] cubrid_bind() doesn't support select bit data from a prepared statement
16)[APIS-596] - [PHP][Manual] The 'test_lob' table which is not created initially may lead some misunderstandings
Changed and Enhanced Features:
1)[APIS-549] - Warnings during PHP/PDO API build via PECL
2)[APIS-555] - support Collection Data Types in Pdo driver
3)[APIS-559] - Compile PHP/PDO drivers from together with CCI source code instead of including the entire CCI binary.
4)[APIS-584] - [PHP][Manual] Some 'Example' codes about the driver in php.net are somewhat confused
5)[APIS-580] - Support CCI connection string parameters like altHosts, loadBalance in PHP/PDO</n>
 <f>959925</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/CUBRID-9.1.0.0004</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.9.1.0.0004.xml"/>
</r>