<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/oci8">oci8</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>2.0.0</v>
 <st>devel</st>
 <l>PHP</l>
 <m>sixd</m>
 <s>Extension for Oracle Database</s>
 <d>This extension allows you to access Oracle Database. OCI8 2.0 can
   be built with PHP 4.3.9 onwards. OCI8 can be linked with Oracle
   Database 9.2, 10, 11, or 12.1 client libraries.  Oracle's standard
   cross-version connectivity applies.  For example PHP linked with
   Oracle Database 11.2 client libraries can connect to Oracle
   Database 9.2 onwards.</d>
 <da>2013-07-24 20:07:01</da>
 <n>- NEW FUNCTIONALITY:

     - Added Implicit Result Set support for Oracle Database 12c.
	Streaming of all IRS's returned from a PL/SQL block is available
	via oci_fetch_array, oci_fetch_assoc, oci_fetch_object and
	oci_fetch_row (but not oci_fetch or oci_fetch_all).
	Alternatively individual IRS statement resources can be obtained
	with the new function 'oci_get_implicit_resultset' and passed to
	any oci_fetch_* function.

     - Added DTrace probes enabled with PHP's generic --enable-dtrace

   - IMPROVED FUNCTIONALITY:

     - Using 'oci_execute($s, OCI_NO_AUTO_COMMIT)' for a SELECT no
	longer unnecessarily initiates an internal ROLLBACK during
	connection close.  This can improve overall scalability by
	reducing &quot;round trips&quot; between PHP and the database.

   - CHANGED FUNCTIONALITY:

     - PHPINFO() CHANGES:

       - The oci8.event and oci8.connection_class values are now shown
         only when the Oracle client libraries support the respective
         functionality.

       - Connection statistics are now in a separate phpinfo() table.

       - Temporary LOB and Collection support status lines in
         phpinfo() were removed.  These features have always been
         enabled since 2007.

     - OCI_INTERNAL_DEBUG() CHANGES:

       - The oci_internal_debug() function is now a no-op.  Use PHP's
         --enable-dtrace functionality with DTrace or SystemTap instead.

   - INTERNAL CHANGES:

     - Fixed a potential NULL pointer dereference flagged by Parfait
       static code analyis.

     - Extended testing of existing OCI8 functionality.

     - Improved test output portability when using the PHP development
       web server to run tests.

     - Removed no-longer necessary unicode patterns from tests
       (vestiges of PHP's previous PHP 6 project)
       
     - Improved build portability by removing compilation type cast
       warnings with some compilers.

     - Fixed compilation warnings when building with Oracle 9.2
       client libraries.

     - Updated code to use internal macro PHP_OCI_REGISTER_RESOURCE.

     - Regularized code prototypes and fixed some in-line documenation
       prototypes.

     - Fixed code folding.</n>
 <f>187534</f>
 <g>http://pecl.php.net/get/oci8-2.0.0</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.2.0.0.xml"/>
</r>