<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/swoole">swoole</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>4.2.11</v>
 <st>stable</st>
 <l>Apache2.0</l>
 <m>tianfenghan</m>
 <s>Event-driven asynchronous and concurrent networking engine with high performance for PHP.</s>
 <d>Event-driven asynchronous and concurrent networking engine with high performance for PHP.
        - event-driven
        - coroutine
        - asynchronous non-blocking
        - multi-thread reactor
        - multi-process worker
        - multi-protocol
        - millisecond timer
        - built-in http/websocket/http2 server
        - coroutine http/websocket client
        - coroutine mysql client
        - coroutine redis client
        - coroutine read/write file system
        - coroutine dns lookup
        - support IPv4/IPv6/UnixSocket/TCP/UDP
        - support SSL/TLS encrypted transmission</d>
 <da>2018-12-28 10:55:39</da>
 <n>+ Support Timer in manager processes
+ Added DNS cache to improve the connection speed of external network services, default TTL60s, capacity 1000 (#2250)
+ When swoole_strerror the second param is 9, it will convert the swoole-specific error code into the text
* Fixed the problem that the connection timeout does not take effect after the client triggers the DNS query. It may cause the coroutine to hang for a long time and connection resource occupation, please update the affected version (v4.2.10) as soon as possible
* Restore Co\Client backward compatibility, connect timeout parameter will change the default timeout of the client
* Fixed the problem that the change does not take place immediately when the client calls the `set` method after the connection
* Fixed the problem that the error code was not updated after the MySQL handshake failed (#2234)
* Fixed a memory error caused by buffer expansion when MySQL executed a large amount of data (e3c5a28)
* Fixed static compilation problem (#2230)
* Async write files to increase the reference count to prevent premature shutdown (028ddf4)
* Fixed Redis Client use illegal parameter would lead to coredump (5af9f3d)
* Fixed the bug that `stack_size` set by `Co::set` is set to the page size of the PHP stack. It is recommended to use the configuration name of `c_stack_size`. Please do not set it without knowing. If your application has C extension hook to zend_execute, you need to pay special attention to setting the C stack, or you don't need to set it
- Remove `enable-debug-log` from PECL compilation configure option, kernel debug logs must be compiled manually to enable</n>
 <f>1263994</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/swoole-4.2.11</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.4.2.11.xml"/>
</r>