<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/swoole">swoole</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>4.2.10</v>
 <st>stable</st>
 <l>Apache2.0</l>
 <m>tianfenghan</m>
 <s>Event-driven asynchronous and concurrent networking engine with high performance for PHP.</s>
 <d>Event-driven asynchronous and concurrent networking engine with high performance for PHP.
        - event-driven
        - coroutine
        - asynchronous non-blocking
        - multi-thread reactor
        - multi-process worker
        - multi-protocol
        - millisecond timer
        - built-in http/websocket/http2 server
        - coroutine http/websocket client
        - coroutine mysql client
        - coroutine redis client
        - coroutine read/write file system
        - coroutine dns lookup
        - support IPv4/IPv6/UnixSocket/TCP/UDP
        - support SSL/TLS encrypted transmission</d>
 <da>2018-12-20 13:04:46</da>
 <n>+ Refactor Coroutine Http Client, developers no longer need to care if the connection is broken unless the network is abnormal  (auto reconnect)
+ The coroutine switch adds some operations, because PDO changes the global error handler at IO request time
+ Support for creating coroutines using internal C functions
+ Allow closed sockets across coroutines
+ Improve server-side SSL certificate verification
+ Enhanced coroutine iterators and stack traces
* swoole_event_wait is always in the first place in the shutdown function list (#2144)
* Unset properties of built-in objects are not allowed, otherwise coredump may be raised
* For most built-in classes, clone and serialization are not allowed.
* Enhanced coroutine redis, now it can use setOption to adjust the configuration after connecting and auto-reconnect like phpredis
* Fixed task wait memory leak
* Fixed epoll error core dump when waiting for writable event on coroutine socket
* Unified coroutine socket timeout (see: https://wiki.swoole.com/wiki/page/p-socket_timeout.html)
* More friendly warning info
* Fixed the enable coroutine bug in the task process
* Fixed defer function not executed when meeting exception
* Fixed a bug about the global buffer was not copied when the write yield
* Fixed Http proxy (#2195) (#2205)
* Fixed Channel push timeout bug (#2226)
* Fixed Http Client websocket mask (#2206)
* Fixed atomic wait in MacOS (#2198)
* Fixed MySQL client recv huge data more than the max length of a single package (#2208) (57fc849) (76179fa)
* Fixed swoole_get_local_mac not supported on macOS (#2199)
* Fixed php_http_parser bug when meeting the wrong header name (5e91557)
* The default sock property value is -1 (0 is STDIN)
- Remove the short name of Co\Server, This name is reserved for future coroutine services
- All asynchronous classes are marked as deprecated
- Remove Timer maximum time limit
- It is not allowed to fork a process in a coroutine</n>
 <f>1257047</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/swoole-4.2.10</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.4.2.10.xml"/>
</r>