<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/swoole">swoole</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>6.0.0</v>
 <st>alpha</st>
 <l>Apache2.0</l>
 <m>tianfenghan</m>
 <s>Event-driven asynchronous and concurrent networking engine with high performance for PHP.</s>
 <d>Event-driven asynchronous and concurrent networking engine with high performance for PHP.
        - event-driven
        - coroutine
        - asynchronous non-blocking
        - multi-thread reactor
        - multi-process worker
        - multi-protocol
        - millisecond timer
        - built-in tcp/http/websocket/http2 server
        - coroutine tcp/http/websocket client
        - coroutine read/write file system
        - coroutine dns lookup
        - support IPv4/IPv6/UnixSocket/TCP/UDP
        - support SSL/TLS encrypted transmission</d>
 <da>2024-06-24 02:46:18</da>
 <n>- Swoole supports multi-threading mode. When PHP is in ZTS mode and Swoole is compiled with --enable-swoole-thread, the multi-threading mode can be utilized.
- Added a new thread management class Swoole\Thread.
- Introduced thread lock Swoole\Thread\Lock.
- Added thread atomic counter Swoole\Thread\Atomic, Swoole\Thread\Atomic\Long.
- Added safe concurrent containers Swoole\Thread\Map, Swoole\Thread\ArrayList, Swoole\Thread\Queue.
- File asynchronous operations support iouring as the underlying engine. Installing liburing and compiling Swoole with --enable-iouring enables asynchronous operations for functions like file_get_contents, file_put_contents, fopen, fclose, fread, fwrite, mkdir, unlink, fsync, fdatasync, rename, fstat, lstat, filesize through iouring.
- Upgraded Boost Context to version 1.84. Now, Loongson CPUs can also supports coroutines.
- Fixed the issue where installation via pecl was not possible.
- Fixed the bug where setting keepalive was not possible for Swoole\Coroutine\FastCGI\Client.
- Fixed the issue where exceeding the max_input_vars would throw an error, causing the process to restart repeatedly.
- Fixed unknown issues caused by using Swoole\Event::wait() within a coroutine.
- Fixed the problem where proc_open does not support pty in coroutine mode.
- Fixed segmentation fault issues with pdo_sqlite on PHP 8.3.
- Fixed unnecessary warnings during the compilation of Swoole.
- Fixed the error thrown by zend_fetch_resource2_ex when STDOUT/STDERR are already closed.
- Fixed ineffective set_tcp_nodelay configuration.
- Fixed the occasional unreachable branch issue during file upload.
- Fixed the problem where setting dispatch_func would cause PHP&#039;s internals to throw errors.
- Fixed the deprecation of AC_PROG_CC_C99 in autoconf &gt;= 2.70.
- Capture exceptions when thread creation fails.
- Fixed the undefined problem with _tsrm_ls_cache.
- Fixed the fatal compile error with GCC 14.
- Removed unnecessary checks for socket structs.
- Upgraded Swoole Library.
- Added support for status code 451 in Swoole\Http\Response.
- Synchronized file operation code across different PHP versions.
- Synchronized pdo operation code across different PHP versions.
- Optimized the code for Socket::ssl_recv().
- Improved config.m4; some configurations can now set library locations via pkg-config.
- Optimized the use of dynamic arrays during request header parsing.
- Optimized file descriptor fd lifecycle issues in multi-threading mode.
- Optimized some fundamental coroutine logic.
- No longer supports PHP 8.0.
- No longer supports Swoole\Coroutine\MySQL coroutine client.
- No longer supports Swoole\Coroutine\Redis coroutine client.
- No longer supports Swoole\Coroutine\PostgreSQL coroutine client.
- Swoole-v6.0.0-alpha is a test version and cannot be used in any production environment; it is for testing purposes only.</n>
 <f>2203556</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/swoole-6.0.0</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.6.0.0.xml"/>
</r>