<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/swoole">swoole</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>6.1.0</v>
 <st>stable</st>
 <l>Apache2.0</l>
 <m>tianfenghan</m>
 <s>Event-driven asynchronous and concurrent networking engine with high performance for PHP.</s>
 <d>Event-driven asynchronous and concurrent networking engine with high performance for PHP.
        - event-driven
        - coroutine
        - asynchronous non-blocking
        - multi-thread reactor
        - multi-process worker
        - multi-protocol
        - millisecond timer
        - built-in tcp/http/websocket/http2 server
        - coroutine tcp/http/websocket client
        - coroutine read/write file system
        - coroutine dns lookup
        - support IPv4/IPv6/UnixSocket/TCP/UDP
        - support SSL/TLS encrypted transmission</d>
 <da>2025-10-24 12:54:28</da>
 <n>Major Changes in Swoole 6.1.0
1. Introduction of &quot;Standard Library Extensions&quot; - Revolutionary Syntax Enhancements
This is the most eye-catching feature at the language level in this update, allowing object-oriented operations on basic types.
Object-Oriented Basic Types: Methods can be called directly on variables of basic types like string, array, and stream (e.g., $text-&gt;length()-&gt;lower()), greatly improving code readability and development experience.
Typed Arrays: Introduced the typed_array syntax, allowing constraints on key and value types, with type checks performed on write operations, enhancing code robustness.

2. A Major Leap in Underlying Architecture and Stability
This version invests heavily in code quality and stability, laying a solid foundation for future development.
Significant Increase in Test Coverage to 86%: By systematically adding test cases, potential errors are greatly reduced, improving the overall reliability and maintainability of the project.
Large-Scale Code Refactoring and Static Analysis: Refactored multiple core modules like Reactor, SSL, and Socket, and used clang-tidy for code standardization, significantly improving code quality and performance.

3. Major Simplification and Unification of the Lock API
A groundbreaking refactoring of the core component for concurrent programming – the lock.
API Simplification: Removed methods like lockwait and trylock, retaining only three core methods – __construct, lock, and unlock – for Swoole\Coroutine\Lock, Swoole\Lock, and Swoole\Thread\Lock.
Unified Behavior: The new API design is closer to PHP&#039;s native flock function, reducing the learning curve, and uses standard constants like LOCK_EX | LOCK_NB to implement advanced features such as non-blocking.

4. Enhanced Coroutine Capabilities and Fine-Grained Control
More flexible coroutine operation capabilities.
Coroutine Cancellation Mechanism: Swoole\Coroutine::cancel() now includes a $throw_exception parameter, allowing a catchable Swoole\Coroutine\CanceledException to be thrown into the target coroutine upon cancellation, enabling safer and more controllable coroutine lifecycle management.
Coroutine State Isolation for Serialization Operations: Fixed the issue of global state isolation for serialize/unserialize in coroutine environments. Global variables related to serialization are now automatically saved and restored during coroutine switches, ensuring isolated serialization contexts for each coroutine.

5. Default HTTP Parser Upgrade, Websocket Feature Enhancements, and Platform Compatibility Improvements
Important improvements in performance and compatibility.
llHTTP Enabled by Default: Replaced the old http_parser with the more performant and modern llhttp, improving the efficiency and reliability of HTTP processing.
WebSocket Feature Enhancements: Both client and server now support receiving fragmented messages, actively disconnecting (disconnect), and sending Ping frames (ping), making the WebSocket protocol implementation more complete.
Deprecating Select, Embracing Poll: Completely deprecated the flawed select event mechanism. On platforms that do not support epoll/kqueue (like Cygwin), poll is now used by default, enabling support for a large number of concurrent connections on these platforms as well.</n>
 <f>2451482</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/swoole-6.1.0</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.6.1.0.xml"/>
</r>