<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/sca_sdo">SCA_SDO</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>1.2.0</v>
 <st>stable</st>
 <l>Apache 2.0</l>
 <m>mfp</m>
 <s>Service Component Architecture (SCA) and Service Data Objects (SDO) for PHP</s>
 <d>Service Data Objects (SDOs) enable PHP applications to work with data from different sources (typically a database query or an XML file) using a single interface. SCA for PHP allows a PHP programmer to write reusable components (classes) in PHP, which can be called either locally, or in a a variety of ways remotely (soap web services, xml-rpc, json-rpc, REST, etc), but always with the same interface.
 
</d>
 <da>2007-05-04 13:17:53</da>
 <n>* Pluggable bindings support
    This support is all in the core. There are now fewer files in the SCA directory and all code specific to a given binding (local, soap, jsonrpc etc.) goes in a subdirectory under the Bindings subdirectory. The SCA core code now just knows how to use the SCA_BindingsFactory object to pull in the classes it needs to service an incoming request. The names of the desired classes are derived from the annotations e.g. if a component has an @binding.soap annotation, the SCA core code will look in SCA/Bindings/soap for the classes it needs. This is probably of limited interest unless you plan to write a binding of your own. We plan an article to describe how this works.

* Refactored bindings based on the pluggable binding support:
    o jsonrpc
    o local (php to php binding)
    o restrpc (RPC based on HTTP GET or POST)
    o soap (SOAP web services)
    o xmlrpc 

* Latest drop of SDO code from Tuscany (currently revision level 532769) including:
    o performance enhancements
    o set of fixes to DataObject destructor to eliminate crashes when the graph is not freed in the default order

* Updates to SDO extension:
    o fix memory leak from SDO_DataObject (depends on Tuscany fixes above)
    o add debug trace macros for debugging memory allocation
    o new signature for SDO_DAS_XML::create() allows an array of schema files to be passed in

* Bug fixes 
    o http://pecl.php.net/bugs/bug.php?id=8428
    o http://pecl.php.net/bugs/bug.php?id=9243
    o http://pecl.php.net/bugs/bug.php?id=9487
    o http://pecl.php.net/bugs/bug.php?id=9991
    o http://pecl.php.net/bugs/bug.php?id=10049
             
* Examples
    o More SCA examples that exercise some of the new bindings, and some of the old, including HelloWorlds and Email scenarios.</n>
 <f>475978</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/SCA_SDO-1.2.0</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.1.2.0.xml"/>
</r>