<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/xdebug">xdebug</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>1.3.0rc2</v>
 <st>beta</st>
 <l>BSD style</l>
 <m>derick</m>
 <s>Provides functions for function traces and profiling</s>
 <d>The Xdebug extension helps you debugging your script by providing a lot of
valuable debug information. The debug information that Xdebug can provide
includes the following:

    * stack and function traces in error messages with:
          o full parameter display for user defined functions
          o function name, file name and line indications
          o support for member functions
    * memory allocation
    * protection for infinite recursions

Xdebug also provides:

    * profiling information for PHP scripts
    * script execution analysis
    * capabilities to debug your scripts interactively with a debug client
</d>
 <da>2003-11-08 14:03:30</da>
 <n>= The error handlers also needs to support the long form &quot;continue&quot; here as
  return command. (Derick)
= Fixed bug in deleting absolute breakpoints on Windows. (Derick)
= Fixed bug #19: The value of xdebug.output_dir in a .htaccess never takes
  effect. (Derick)
= Fixed bug #27: Repeated connect attempts when no debugger is listening.
  (Derick)
= Fixed handling stack traces for when display_errors was set to Off. (Derick)
= Fixed segfault where a function name didn't exist in case of a
 &quot;call_user_function&quot;. (Derick)
= Fixed reading a filename in case of an callback to a PHP function from an
  internal function (like &quot;array_map()&quot;). (Derick)
= Fixed bug with wrong file names for functions called from call_user_*().
  (Derick)
+ Added the option &quot;dump_superglobals&quot; to the remote debugger. If you set this
  option to 0 the &quot;show-local&quot; and similar commands will not return any data
  from superglobals anymore. (Derick)
= Fixed bug #2: &quot;pear package&quot; triggers a segfault. (Derick)
= Fixed crash bug when a function had sprintf style parameters (ie.
  strftime()). (Derick)
+ Added &quot;id&quot; attribute to &lt;var /&gt; elements in responses from the remove
  debugger when the response method is XML. This makes it possible to
  distinguish between unique elements by use of recursion for example. (Derick)
= Improved performance greatly by doing lazy folding of variables outside
  trace mode. (Derick)
= Fixed a bug with &quot;quit&quot;, if it was used it disabled the extension for the
  current process. (Derick)
+ Added the &quot;full&quot; argument to the remote command &quot;backtrace&quot;. When this
  argument is passed, the local variables will be returned to for each frame in
  the stack. (Derick)
+ Implemented xdebug_time_index() which returns the time passed since the
  start of the script. This change also changes the output of the tracing
  functions as the start time will no longer be the first function call, but
  the real start time of the script. (Derick)
+ Implemented the &quot;show-local&quot; command (shows all local variables in the
  current scope including all contents). (Derick)
+ Implemented conditions for breakpoints in the &quot;break&quot; command. (Derick)</n>
 <f>153048</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/xdebug-1.3.0rc2</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.1.3.0rc2.xml"/>
</r>