<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/xdebug">xdebug</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>2.0.0RC2</v>
 <st>beta</st>
 <l>BSD style</l>
 <m>derick</m>
 <s>Provides functions for function traces and profiling</s>
 <d>The Xdebug extension helps you debugging your script by providing a lot of
valuable debug information. The debug information that Xdebug can provide
includes the following:

    * stack and function traces in error messages with:
          o full parameter display for user defined functions
          o function name, file name and line indications
          o support for member functions
    * memory allocation
    * protection for infinite recursions

Xdebug also provides:

    * profiling information for PHP scripts
    * script execution analysis
    * capabilities to debug your scripts interactively with a debug client</d>
 <da>2006-12-24 09:46:43</da>
 <n>Sun, Dec 24, 2006 - xdebug 2.0.0rc2
+ Added new features:
	- Implemented the &quot;xdebug.var_display_max_children&quot; setting. The default is
	  set to 128 children.
	- Added types to fancy var dumping function.
	- Implemented FR #210: Add a way to stop the debug session without having
	  to execute a script. The GET/POST parameter &quot;XDEBUG_SESSION_STOP_NO_EXEC&quot;
	  works in the same way as XDEBUG_SESSION_STOP, except that the script will
	  not be executed.
	- DBGP: Allow postmortem analysis.
	- DBGP: Added the non-standard function xcmd_profiler_name_get.

+ Changes:
	- Fixed the issue where xdebug_get_declared_vars() did not know about
	  variables there are in the declared function header, but were not used in
	  the code. Due to this change expected arguments that were not send to a
	  function will now show up as ??? in stack and function traces in PHP 5.1
	  and PHP 5.2.
	- Allow xdebug.var_display_max_data and xdebug.var_display_max_depth
	  settings of -1 which will unlimit those settings.
	- DBGP: Sort super globals in Globals overview.
	- DBGP: Fixed a bug where error messages where not added upon errors in the
	  protocol.
	- DBGP: Change context 1 from globals (superglobals + vars in bottom most
	  stack frame) to just superglobals.

= Fixed bugs:
	- Fixed linking error on AIX by adding libm.
	- Fixed dead code analysis for THROW.
	- Fixed oparray prefill caching for code coverage.
	- Fixed the xdebug.remote_log feature work.
	- DBGP: Fixed a bug where $this did not appear in the local scoped context.
	- DBGP: Reimplemented property_set to use the same symbol fetching function
	  as property_get. We now only use eval in case no type (-t) argument was
	  given.
	- DBGP: Fixed some issues with finding out the classname, which is
	  important for fetching private properties.
	- DBGP: Fixed usage of uninitialized memory that prevented looking up
	  numerical array keys while fetching array elements not work properly.
	- Fixed bug #228: Binary safety for stream output and property fetches.
	- Fixed bug #227: The SESSION super global does not show up in the Globals
	  scope.
	- Fixed bug #225: xdebug dumps core when protocol is GDB.
	- Fixed bug #224: Compile failure on Solaris.
	- Fixed bug #219: Memory usage delta in traces don't work on PHP 5.2.0.
	- Fixed bug #215: Cannot retrieve nested arrays when the array key is a
	  numeric index.
	- Fixed bug #214: The depth level of arrays was incorrectly checked so it
	  would show the first page of a level too deep as well.
	- Fixed bug #213: Dead code analysis doesn't take catches for throws into
	  account.
	- Fixed bug #211: When starting a new session with a different idekey, the
	  cookie is not updated.
	- Fixed bug #209: Additional remote debugging session started when
	  triggering shutdown function.
	- Fixed bug #208: Socket connection attempted when XDEBUG_SESSION_STOP.
	- Fixed PECL bug #8989: Compile error with PHP 5 and GCC 2.95.</n>
 <f>259763</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/xdebug-2.0.0RC2</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.2.0.0RC2.xml"/>
</r>