<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/xdebug">xdebug</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>2.0.0RC1</v>
 <st>beta</st>
 <l>BSD style</l>
 <m>derick</m>
 <s>Provides functions for function traces and profiling</s>
 <d>The Xdebug extension helps you debugging your script by providing a lot of
valuable debug information. The debug information that Xdebug can provide
includes the following:

    * stack and function traces in error messages with:
          o full parameter display for user defined functions
          o function name, file name and line indications
          o support for member functions
    * memory allocation
    * protection for infinite recursions

Xdebug also provides:

    * profiling information for PHP scripts
    * script execution analysis
    * capabilities to debug your scripts interactively with a debug client</d>
 <da>2006-10-08 17:12:22</da>
 <n>+ Added new features:
    - Implemented FR #70: Provide optional depth on xdebug_call_* functions.
    - Partially implemented FR #50: Resource limiting for variable display. By
      default only two levels of nested variables and max string lengths of 512
      are shown. This can be changed by setting the ini settings
      xdebug.var_display_max_depth and xdebug.var_display_max_data.
    - Implemented breakpoints for different types of PHP errors. You can now
      set an 'exception' breakpoint on &quot;Fatal error&quot;, &quot;Warning&quot;, &quot;Notice&quot; etc.
      This is related to bug #187.
    - Added the xdebug_print_function_trace() function to display a stack trace on
      demand.
    - Reintroduce HTML tracing by adding a new tracing option &quot;XDEBUG_TRACE_HTML&quot;
      (4).
    - Made xdebug_stop_trace() return the trace file name, so that the
      following works: 
    - Added the xdebug.collect_vars setting to tell Xdebug to collect
      information about which variables are used in a scope. Now you don't need
      to show variables with xdebug.show_local_vars anymore for
      xdebug_get_declared_vars() to work.
    - Make the filename parameter to the xdebug_start_trace() function
      optional. If left empty it will use the same algorithm to pick a filename
      as when you are using the xdebug.auto_trace setting.

+ Changes:
    - Implemented dead code analysis during code coverage for:
      * abstract methods.
      * dead code after return, throw and exit.
      * implicit returns when a normal return is present.
    - Improved readability of stack traces.
    - Use PG(html_errors) instead of checking whether we run with CLI when
      deciding when to use HTML messages or plain text messages.

= Fixed bugs:
    - Fixed bug #203: PHP errors with HTML content processed incorrectly. This
      patch backs out the change that was made to fix bug #182.
    - Fixed bug #198: Segfault when trying to use a non-existing debug handler.
    - Fixed bug #197: Race condition fixes created too many files.
    - Fixed bug #196: Profile timing on Windows does not work.
    - Fixed bug #195: CLI Error after debugging session.
    - Fixed bug #193: Compile problems with PHP 5.2.
    - Fixed bug #191: File/line breakpoints are case-sensitive on Windows.
    - Fixed bug #181: Xdebug doesn't handle uncaught exception output
      correctly.
    - Fixed bug #173: Coverage produces wrong coverage.
    - Fixed a typo that prevented the XDEBUG_CONFIG option &quot;profiler_enable&quot;
      from working.</n>
 <f>252286</f>
 <g>http://pecl.php.net/get/xdebug-2.0.0RC1</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.2.0.0RC1.xml"/>
</r>