<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/xdebug">xdebug</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>2.0.0beta6</v>
 <st>beta</st>
 <l>BSD style</l>
 <m>derick</m>
 <s>Provides functions for function traces and profiling</s>
 <d>The Xdebug extension helps you debugging your script by providing a lot of
valuable debug information. The debug information that Xdebug can provide
includes the following:

    * stack and function traces in error messages with:
          o full parameter display for user defined functions
          o function name, file name and line indications
          o support for member functions
    * memory allocation
    * protection for infinite recursions

Xdebug also provides:

    * profiling information for PHP scripts
    * script execution analysis
    * capabilities to debug your scripts interactively with a debug client</d>
 <da>2006-06-30 05:32:29</da>
 <n>+ Added new features:
    - Implemented FR #137: feature_get for general commands doesn't have a text field.
    - Implemented FR #131: XDebug needs to implement paged child object requests.
    - Implemented FR #124: Add backtrace dumping information when exception thrown.
    - Implemented FR #70: Add feature_get breakpoint_types.
    - Added profiling aggregation functions (patch by Andrei Zmievski)
    - Implemented the &quot;timestamp&quot; option for the xdebug.trace_output_name and
      xdebug.profiler_output_name settings.
    - Added the xdebug.remote_log setting that allows you to log debugger
      communication to a log file for debugging. This can also be set through
      the &quot;remote_log&quot; element in the XDEBUG_CONFIG environment variable.
    - Added a &quot;script&quot; value to the profiler_output_name option.  This will write
      the profiler output to a filename that consists of the script's full path
      (using underscores). ie: /var/www/index.php becomes
      var_www_index_php_cachegrind.out. (Patch by Brian Shire).
    - DBGp: Implemented support for hit conditions for breakpoints.
    - DBGp: Added support for conditions for file/line breakpoints.
    - DBGp: Added support for hit value checking to file/line breakpoints.
    - DBGp: Added support for &quot;exception&quot; breakpoints.

+ Performance improvements:
    - Added a cache that prevents the code coverage functionality from running a
      &quot;which code is executable check&quot; on every function call, even if they
      were executed multiple times. This should speed up code coverage a lot.
    - Speedup Xdebug but only gathering information about variables in scopes when
      either remote debugging is used, or show_local_vars is enabled.

= Fixed bugs:
    - Fixed bug #184: problem with control chars in code traces
    - Fixed bug #183: property_get -n $this-&gt;somethingnonexistent crashes the
      debugger.
    - Fixed bug #182: Errors are not html escaped when being displayed.
    - Fixed bug #180: collected includes not shown in trace files. (Patch by
      Cristian Rodriguez)
    - Fixed bug #178: $php_errormsg and Track errors unavailable.
    - Fixed bug #177: debugclient fails to compile due to Bison.
    - Fixed bug #176: Segfault using SplTempFileObject.
    - Fixed bug #173: Xdebug segfaults using SPL ArrayIterator.
    - Fixed bug #171: set_time_limit stack overflow on 2nd request.
    - Fixed bug #168: Xdebug's DBGp crashes on an eval command where the
      result is an array.
    - Fixed bug #125: show_mem_delta does not calculate correct negative values on
      64bit machines.
    - Fixed bug #121: property_get -n $r[2] returns the whole hash.
    - Fixed bug #111: xdebug does not ignore set_time_limit() function during debug
      session.
    - Fixed bug #87: Warning about headers when &quot;register_shutdown_function&quot; used.
    - Fixed PECL bug #6940 (XDebug ignores set_time_limit)
    - Fixed Komodo bug 45484: no member data for objects in PHP debugger.
    - Suppress NOP/EXT_NOP from being marked as executable code with Code
      Coverage.</n>
 <f>242013</f>
 <g>http://pecl.php.net/get/xdebug-2.0.0beta6</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.2.0.0beta6.xml"/>
</r>