<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/xdebug">xdebug</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>2.1.0beta1</v>
 <st>beta</st>
 <l>BSD style</l>
 <m>derick</m>
 <s>Provides functions for function traces and profiling</s>
 <d>The Xdebug extension helps you debugging your script by providing a lot of
valuable debug information. The debug information that Xdebug can provide
includes the following:

    * stack and function traces in error messages with:
          o full parameter display for user defined functions
          o function name, file name and line indications
          o support for member functions
    * memory allocation
    * protection for infinite recursions

Xdebug also provides:

    * profiling information for PHP scripts
    * code coverage analysis
    * capabilities to debug your scripts interactively with a debug client</d>
 <da>2010-01-02 19:33:21</da>
 <n>Sun, Jan 03, 2010 - xdebug 2.1.0beta1

+ Added features:
	- Added error display collection and suppressions.
	- Added the recording of headers being set in scripts.
	- Added variable assignment tracing.
	- Added the ability to turn of the default overriding of var_dump().
	- Added &quot;Scream&quot; support, which disables the @ operator.
	- Added a trace-file analysing script.
	- Added support for debugging into phars.
	- Added a default xdebug.ini. (Patch by Martin Schuhfu
	  &lt;martins@spot-media.de&gt;)
	- Added function parameters in computerized function traces.
	- PHP 5.3 compatibility.
	- Improved code coverage accuracy.

  + New functions:
	- xdebug_get_formatted_function_stack(), which returns a formatted function
	  stack instead of displaying it.
	- xdebug_get_headers(), which returns all headers that have been set in a
	  script, both explicitly with things like header(), but also implicitly
	  for things like setcookie().
	- xdebug_start_error_collection(), xdebug_stop_error_collection() and
	  xdebug_get_collected_errors(), which allow you to collect all notices,
	  warnings and error messages that Xdebug generates from PHP's
	  error_reporting functionality so that you can output them at a later
	  point in your script by hand.

  + New settings:
	- xdebug.collect_assignments, which enables the emitting of variable
	  assignments in function traces.
	- xdebug.file_line_format, to generate a link with a specific format for 
	  every filename that Xdebug outputs.
	- xdebug.overload_var_dump, which allows you to turn off Xdebug's version
	  of var_dump().
	- xdebug.remote_cookie_expire_time, that controls the length of a
	  remote debugging session. (Patch by Rick Pannen &lt;pannen@gmail.com&gt;)
	- xdebug.scream, which makes the @ operator to be ignored.

+ Changes:
	- Added return values for xdebug_start_code_coverage() and
	  xdebug_stop_code_coverage() to indicate whether the action was
	  succesfull.  xdebug_start_code_coverage() will return TRUE if the call
	  enabled code coverage, and FALSE if it was already enabled.
	  xdebug_stop_code_coverage() will return FALSE when code coverage wasn't
	  started yet and TRUE if it was turned on.
	- Added an optional argument to xdebug_print_function_stack() to display
	  your own message. (Patch by Mikko Koppanen).
	- All HTML output as generated by Xdebug now has a HTML &quot;class&quot; attribute
	  for easy CSS formatting.

- Removed features:
	- Support for PHP versions lower than PHP 5.1 have been dropped.
	- The PHP3 and GDB debugger engines have been removed.

= Fixed bugs:
	- Fixed support for showing $this in remote debugging sessions.
	- Fixed bug in formatting the display of &quot;Variables in the local scope&quot;.
	- Possible fix for a threading issue where the headers gathering function
	  would create stack overflows.
	- Possible fix for #324: xdebug_dump_superglobals() only dumps superglobals
	  that were accessed before, and #478: XDebug 2.0.x can't use %R in
	  xdebug.profiler_output_name if register_long_arrays is off.

	- Fixed bug #505: %s in xdebug.trace_output_name breaks functions traces.
	- Fixed bug #494: Private attributes of parent class unavailable when
	  inheriting.
	- Fixed bug #486: feature_get -n breakpoint_types returns out of date list.
	- Fixed bug #476: Xdebug doesn't support PHP 5.3's exception chaining.
	- Fixed bug #472: Dead Code Analysis for code coverage messed up after goto.
	- Fixed bug #470: Catch blocks marked as dead code unless executed.
	- Fixed bug #469: context_get for function variables always appear as
	  &quot;uninitialized&quot;.
	- Fixed bug #468: Property_get on $GLOBALS works only at top-level, by
	  adding GLOBALS to the super globals context.
	- Fixed bug #453: Memory leaks.
	- Fixed bug #445: error_prepend_string and error_append_string are ignored
	  by xdebug_error_cb. (Patch by Kent Davidson &lt;kent@marketruler.com&gt;)
	- Fixed bug #442: configure: error: &quot;you have strange libedit&quot;.
	- Fixed bug #439: Xdebug crash in xdebug_header_handler.
	- Fixed bug #423: Conflicts with funcall.
	- Fixed bug #419: Make use of P_tmpdir if defined instead of hard coded
	  '/tmp'.
	- Fixed bug #417: Response of context_get may lack page and pagesize
	  attributes.
	- Fixed bug #411: Class/function breakpoint setting does not follow the
	  specs.
	- Fixed bug #393: eval returns array data at the previous page request.
	- Fixed bug #391: Xdebug doesn't stop executing script on catchable fatal
	  errors.
	- Fixed bug #389: Destructors called on fatal error.
	- Fixed bug #368: Xdebug's debugger bails out on a parse error with the
	  eval command.
	- Fixed bug #356: Temporary breakpoints persist.
	- Fixed bug #355: Function numbers in trace files weren't unique.
	- Fixed bug #340: Segfault while throwing an Exception.
	- Fixed bug #328: Private properties are incorrectly enumerated in case of
	  extended classes.
	- Fixed bug #249: Xdebug's error handler messes up with the SOAP
	  extension's error handler.

+ DBGP:
	- Fixed cases where private properties where shown for objects, but not
	  accessible.
	- Added a patch by Lucas Nealan (lucas@php.net) and Brian Shire
	  (shire@php.net) of Facebook to allow connections to the initiating
	  request's IP address for remote debugging.
	- Added the -p argument to the eval command as well, pending inclusion into
	  DBGP.
	- Added the retrieval of a file's execution lines. I added a new
	  un-official method called xcmd_get_executable_lines which requires the
	  stack depth as argument (-d). You can only fetch this information for
	  stack frames as it needs an available op-array which is only available
	  when a function is executed.
	- Added a fake &quot;CLASSNAME&quot; property to objects that are returned in debug
	  requests to facilitate deficiencies in IDEs that fail to show the &quot;classname&quot;
	  XML attribute.</n>
 <f>295579</f>
 <g>http://pecl.php.net/get/xdebug-2.1.0beta1</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.2.1.0beta1.xml"/>
</r>
