<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/xdebug">xdebug</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>2.2.0RC1</v>
 <st>stable</st>
 <l>BSD style</l>
 <m>derick</m>
 <s>Provides functions for function traces and profiling</s>
 <d>The Xdebug extension helps you debugging your script by providing a lot of
valuable debug information. The debug information that Xdebug can provide
includes the following:

    * stack and function traces in error messages with:
          o full parameter display for user defined functions
          o function name, file name and line indications
          o support for member functions
    * memory allocation
    * protection for infinite recursions

Xdebug also provides:

    * profiling information for PHP scripts
    * code coverage analysis
    * capabilities to debug your scripts interactively with a debug client</d>
 <da>2012-03-13 08:49:37</da>
 <n>Tue, Mar 13, 2012 - xdebug 2.2.0rc1

+ Added features:

    - Support for PHP 5.4.

	- Added ANSI colour output for the shell. (Including patches by Michael
	  Maclean)
	- Added var_dump() overloading on the command line (issue #457).

	- Added better support for closures in stack and function traces.
	- Added the size of arrays to the overloaded variable output, so that you
	  know how many elements there are.
	- Added support for X-HTTP-FORWARDED-FOR before falling back to REMOTE_ADDR
	  (issue #660). (Patch by Hannes Magnusson)
	- Added the method call type to xdebug_get_function_stack() (issue #695). 

	- Added extra information to error printouts to tell that the error
	  suppression operator has been ignored due to xdebug.scream.
    - Added a error-specific CSS class to stack traces.


+ New settings:

	- xdebug.cli_color for colouring output on the command line (Unix only).
	- Added xdebug.trace_enable_trigger to triger function traces through a
	  GET/POST/COOKIE parameter (issue #517). (Patch by Patrick Allaert)
	- Added support for the 'U' format specifier for function trace and
	  profiler filenames.

+ Changes:

	- Improved performance by lazy-initializing data structures.
	- Improved code coverage performance. (Including some patches by Taavi
	  Burns)
	- Improved compatibility with KCacheGrind.
	- Improved logging of remote debugging connections, by added connection
	  success/failure logging to the xdebug.remote_log functionality.

= Fixed bugs:

	- No additional bug fixes besides the ones from the 2.1 branch up til
	  Xdebug 2.1.4.</n>
 <f>244336</f>
 <g>http://pecl.php.net/get/xdebug-2.2.0RC1</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.2.2.0RC1.xml"/>
</r>