<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/xdebug">xdebug</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>2.6.0alpha1</v>
 <st>beta</st>
 <l>BSD style</l>
 <m>derick</m>
 <s>Provides functions for function traces and profiling</s>
 <d>The Xdebug extension helps you debugging your script by providing a lot of
valuable debug information. The debug information that Xdebug can provide
includes the following:

    * stack and function traces in error messages with:
          o full parameter display for user defined functions
          o function name, file name and line indications
          o support for member functions
    * memory allocation
    * protection for infinite recursions

Xdebug also provides:

    * profiling information for PHP scripts
    * code coverage analysis
    * capabilities to debug your scripts interactively with a debug client</d>
 <da>2017-12-02 19:25:20</da>
 <n>Sat, Dec  2, 2018 - xdebug 2.6.0alpha1

+ Added features:

  - Implemented issue #474: Added &quot;memory&quot; output to profiling files, to find out where memory is allocated.
  - Implemented issue #575: Dump super globals contents to error log upon errors, just like when this would happen for stack traces.
  - Implemented issue #964: Parse X-Forwarded-For for the first IP address when selecting the remote_connect_back host (Steve Easley).
  - Implemented issue #990: Add DBGp: notifications for notices and warnings to be shown in IDEs.
  - Implemented issue #1312: Implement extended_properties feature to remote debugging to support names and values with low ASCII values.
  - Implemented issue #1323: Added xdebug.filename_format setting to configure the formatting of filenames when tracing.
  - Implemented issue #1379: Added support for Unix domain sockets to xdebug.remote_host (Sara Golemon).
  - Implemented issue #1380: Added xdebug_is_debugger_active() that returns true when debugger is connected.
  - Implemented issue #1391: Added support for earlier stack frames through new argument for xdebug_call_* functions.
  - Implemented issue #1420: Handle PHP 7.2's new methods for switch/case
  - Implemented issue #1470: Added xdebug.remote_timeout to make connect timeout configurable.
  - Implemented issue #1495: Make var_dump() also use the new xdebug.filename_format when formatting filenames.

+ Improvements:

  - Implemented issue #847: Added support for &quot;%s&quot; specifier for xdebug.trace_output_name.
  - Implemented issue #1384: Compile warning on Ubuntu 16.04 with GCC 5.4.x.
  - Implemented issue #1401: Improved error message in case the connection breaks.
  - Implemented issue #1430: Change DBGp tests to use TEST_PHP_EXECUTABLE instead of hard coded 'php'
  - Implemented issue #1484: Use FD_CLOEXEC with debugging sockets to prevent FDs from leaking to forked processes (Chris Wright).
  - Improve the foldexpr in xt.vim to fold lines correctly (Donie Leigh).

= Fixed bugs:

  - Fixed issue #1272: property_get doesn't return @attributes for SimpleXMLElement.
  - Fixed issue #1305: Property names with quotes can not be fetch while debugging.
  - Fixed issue #1431: Fix &quot;use after free&quot; with in add_name_attribute_or_element.
  - Fixed issue #1432: Fixed memory leak with xdebug_path_info_dtor.
  - Fixed issue #1449: Debugging breaks with array element keys containing low-ASCII variables.
  - Fixed issue #1471: Tracing crashes with return_assignments and ternairy operator.
  - Fixed issue #1474: Crashes due to variable resolving/reading mechanism not taking care of temporary hash tables correctly (Nikita Popov, Derick).
  - Fixed issue #1481: Fixed s390x and ppc64 builds (Remi Collet).
  - Fixed issue #1486: Crash on ZEND_SWITCH_LONG / ZEND_SWITCH_STRING with more than 32 cases.
  - Fixed issue #1496: Rewrite README.rst to be more clear on how to install and build Xdebug.

~ Changes:

  - Fixed issue #1411: Use Error (Throwable) instead of fatal error when maximum nesting level is reached.

- Removed features:

  - Implemented issue #1377: Drop support for PHP 5.5 and 5.6, only PHP 7 is now supported</n>
 <f>276350</f>
 <g>http://pecl.php.net/get/xdebug-2.6.0alpha1</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.2.6.0alpha1.xml"/>
</r>