<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/xdebug">xdebug</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>3.4.3</v>
 <st>stable</st>
 <l>Xdebug-1.03</l>
 <m>derick</m>
 <s>Xdebug is a debugging and productivity extension for PHP</s>
 <d>Xdebug and provides a range of features to improve the PHP development
experience.

Step Debugging
    A way to step through your code in your IDE or editor while the script is
    executing.

Improvements to PHP&#039;s error reporting
    An improved var_dump() function, stack traces for Notices, Warnings, Errors
    and Exceptions to highlight the code path to the error

Tracing
    Writes every function call, with arguments and invocation location to disk.
    Optionally also includes every variable assignment and return value for
    each function.

Profiling
    Allows you, with the help of visualisation tools, to analyse the
    performance of your PHP application and find bottlenecks.

Code Coverage Analysis
    To show which parts of your code base are executed when running unit tests
    with PHP Unit.</d>
 <da>2025-05-14 09:51:52</da>
 <n>Wed, May 14, 2025 - Xdebug 3.4.3

= Fixed bugs:

  - Fixed issue #2322: Xdebug tries to open debugging connection in destructors during shutdown
  - Fixed issue #2325: Referred chrome browser extension is no longer working
  - Fixed issue #2326: Step debugger finishes if property debugging handler in PHP throws an exception
  - Fixed issue #2331: Segmentation fault with &#039;invalid&#039; variable names
  - Fixed issue #2339: Trying to throw an exception can cause a zend_mm_heap corrupted error under specific circumstances
  - Fixed issue #2340: Xdebug case sensitivity issues on some files introduced since 3.3.0
  - Fixed issue #2343: Fatal error on virtual property hook step debugging
  - Fixed issue #2348: Xdebug does not resolve breakpoints in property hooks</n>
 <f>262647</f>
 <g>https://pecl.php.net/get/xdebug-3.4.3</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.3.4.3.xml"/>
</r>