<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<r xmlns="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release
    http://pear.php.net/dtd/rest.release.xsd">
 <p xlink:href="/rest/p/mongodb">mongodb</p>
 <c>pecl.php.net</c>
 <v>1.0.0beta2</v>
 <st>beta</st>
 <l>New BSD License</l>
 <m>jmikola</m>
 <s>MongoDB driver for PHP</s>
 <d>The purpose of this driver is to provide exceptionally thin glue between MongoDB
and PHP, implementing only fundemental and performance-critical components
necessary to build a fully-functional MongoDB driver.</d>
 <da>2015-10-06 05:55:06</da>
 <n>* PHPC-442: report PHP version in debug info
* PHPC-409: $readPreference is no longer sent to non-mongos nodes
* PHPC-438: Debug handler should display null for no WC error
* PHPC-436: Handle new writeConcernErrors array in mongoc_write_result_t
* PHPC-415: Add testcase
* PHPC-415: SSL/TLS already set-up for this stream
* PHPC-393: Ignore non-public properties when encoding BSON
* PHPC-430, PHPC-377: Do not convert Query filter arg to an object
* PHPC-377: Eliminate object casting and whole lot of zend hash helpers
* PHPC-373: Get rid of MAKE_STD_ZVAL() and use bson_t instead
* PHPC-430: Regression tests for Query arg corruption
* PHPC-379: I broke PHP5.3 build. Thats OK, since we don't support it.
* PHPC-427: Fix parsing of null WC journal param for PHP 5.4
* PHPC-428: Remove support for WriteConcern fsync option
* PHPC-427: Do not set WC journal/fsync to false for NULL args
* PHPC-423: WriteConcern should report default &quot;w&quot; option as null
* PHPC-426: WC ctor should throw for invalid $w and $wtimeout args
* PHPC-425: WC ctor should accept int/string $w args w/o casting
* PHPC-412: HHVM does not do SSL peer verification like PHP
* PHPC-410: Make BSON exception message consistent with HHVM
* PHPC-410: zval_to_bson() should throw on non-Serializable Type objects
* PHPC-410: object_to_bson() should throw on unsupported BSON\Type objects
* PHPC-410: object_to_bson() should encode non-stdClass objects
* PHPC-418: Getters for WriteConcern properties
* PHPC-418: Getters for ReadPreference properties
* PHPC-417: Return value objects from Manager RP/WC getters
* PHPC-408: Ensure object_to_bson() always creates a BSON document</n>
 <f>605906</f>
 <g>http://pecl.php.net/get/mongodb-1.0.0beta2</g>
 <x xlink:href="package.1.0.0beta2.xml"/>
</r>